AI Research Explained
视频AI的下一个突破口，不在于更大的模型，而在于更聪明的“后训练”方法。面对碎片化的研究现状，这篇开创性综述首次提出了SFT、RL、TTS三大支柱，为Video-LMM如何真正理解视频构建了第一个清晰框架。
Hello everyone, and welcome. We interact with video content almost daily, and a
long-standing goal in AI has been to enable machines to understand the complex
dynamics within these videos, just like humans do. Recently, Video Large
Multimodal Models, or Video-LMMs, have made significant strides in understanding
Before we dive into our main topic, let's set the stage with some background.
Large Multimodal Models, or LMMs, like the well-known GPT-4V, can already
understand both images and text. When we extend this capability to the video
domain, we get Video-LMMs. However, video is far more complex than a static
Since this paper is a survey, our contribution isn't a new model that sets a
state-of-the-art record. Instead, through a systematic review, we demonstrate
the immense value of post-training methods across a wide range of applications.
For complex spatio-temporal reasoning, like analyzing tactical plays in a sports
This paper represents a landmark contribution to the field. For the first time,
it provides a clear and systematic framework for the somewhat fragmented
research area of Video-LMM post-training. Our 'three-pillar' classification not
only helps researchers understand the connections between existing works but
In conclusion, this paper offers a comprehensive guide to the advanced evolution
of Video-LMMs. It systematically organizes the core methodologies for enhancing
video reasoning capabilities through a taxonomy built on three pillars:
Supervised Fine-Tuning with Chain-of-Thought, Reinforcement Learning-based
Thanks for watching!