AI Research Explained
当业界争相堆砌千亿参数时，150亿参数的Apriel-15B竟在单GPU上追平Gemini和Claude！它如何通过三阶段训练法，用数据智慧替代算力暴力，在十大图像基准测试中实现52分标杆成绩？
Today we'll explore a groundbreaking AI research breakthrough -
Apriel-1.5-15B-Thinker. What makes this work particularly exciting is how it
demonstrates that achieving cutting-edge multimodal reasoning capabilities
doesn't necessarily require massive computing clusters or extensive parameter
Current multimodal large models face a significant contradiction: improvements
in model performance often come with dramatic parameter expansion and
exponential growth in computational requirements. This means most cutting-edge
models can only run on large computing clusters, severely limiting their
April-1.5-15B-Thinker's core innovation lies in its progressive three-stage
training framework. The first stage involves depth expansion, scaling the base
model from 12 billion to 15 billion parameters. This isn't merely adding
parameters but involves specific architectural adjustments that significantly
In performance evaluation, Apriel-1.5-15B-Thinker achieved a score of 52 on the
Artificial Analysis Intelligence Index, matching the performance of
DeepSeek-R1-0528. Even more impressive is that across ten image benchmark tests,
its average performance was within 5 percentage points of both Gemini-2.5-Flash
This work holds significant academic importance by redefining the development
path for multimodal models. It demonstrates that sophisticated training strategy
design can achieve cutting-edge performance with limited computational
resources, challenging the traditional notion that bigger is always better. This
Thanks for watching!